JESSE BRADBURY

Phoenix, AZ

Phone: 480-326-8355 | Email: Bradburyjesse7@gmail.com LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/jessebradbury Portfolio: https://jessebradbury.github.io/Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with a background in education and technical support. Currently enrolled in the Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp with Arizona State University. Proficient in designing and developing the front end and back end of websites and applications. Experience working in fast-paced development environments with tight deadlines. Agile learner, capable of dealing with ambiguity through collaboration and utilization of resources.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software Languages: JavaScript, Node, Express, React, SQL, MongoDB, CSS, HTML

Softwares/Platforms: Heroku, Shopify

PROJECTS

SlinkyWorld

<u>qithub.com/JesseBradbury/Slinky-Project</u> | <u>slinkyworld-4cca5764620e.herokuapp.com</u>

- Full stack web application for people to record their favorite public staircases to use a Slinky. Users can create an account, post about the locations they like using their slinky, and comment on each location about how fast their slinky descended the stairs.
- My responsibilities for the project were creating the express routes for all functions on the website. I was also responsible for formatting the handlebars templates.
- This application uses Node.js and Express.js to create a RESTfulAPI, uses
 Handlebars.js for the template engine, and uses MySQL and Sequelize ORM for
 handling the data in our database.

SQL Employee Tracker

<u>qithub.com/JesseBradbury/SQL-Employee-Tracker</u>

- Command line content management system that can be used to manage an employee database. Allows user to manage departments, roles, and employees in a company.
- This application uses Node.js and MySQL for the database, and uses inquirer to allow the user to interact with the data in the command line.

All About Plants!

github.com/nicklearning/plant-info-project | nicklearning.github.io/plant-info-project

- Website that allows users to search for plants and provides important information about growing and caring for them. Users can save their favorite
- My responsibilities included setting up the functions to search the API for the correct plants, and formatting the returned data to fit the needs of our application.
- This project is a practice in manipulating data returned from an API, and using JavaScript to dynamically create elements on the page based on the user's search.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Genius 2017 – Present **Apple** Chandler, AZ

Responsible for troubleshooting and documenting Apple software and hardware issues, dedicated to showing empathy and patience while swiftly resolving customers issues or concerns. Certified Mac and iOS repair technician highly skilled in problem solving and efficient issue resolution.

Key Accomplishments:

- Top performer in NPS and business engagement over multiple quarters, maintained a promoter streak of 100+ responses over 2 quarters in 2023.
- Mentored team members of the Genius Bar to improve specific aspects of the customer experience and facilitated additional technical training for new technicians.
- Selected as the Training Lead, responsible for onboarding and mentoring over 40 team members and facilitating group trainings for new product launch.
- Chosen for a Career Experience with the Learning and Development team as an Instructional Designer where I collaborated with stakeholders and subject matter experts to author training content featured globally across Apple Retail.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Business Teacher Mesa High School 2014 – 2017

Mesa, AZ

Taught courses in Computer Science, Computer Basics, Video Game Development, Career Explorations, Percussion and Marching Band. Designed digital curriculum and assessments for Career and Technical Education Courses. Trained fellow teachers on eLearning software and online course management.

Key Accomplishments:

- Piloted the first AP Computer Science courses in 2017 with 50% of applicable students receiving AP credits by passing rigorous assessments.
- Nominated by school administration as the Rookie Teacher of the Year in 2014, an award for the the most outgoing and promising first year teacher.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

Anticipated graduation of April 2024

A 24 week intensive program focused on gaining skills in web development, including JavaScript, Node, SQL, MongoDB, and React.

Bachelors in Secondary Education- Business: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

Business education with a focus in teaching computers. Member of the Leadership Scholarship Program, ASU Marching Band and Drumline, Devil's Advocate tour guides.